WELCOME TO THE DAILY SHOW.
>> [screaming]
>> MAN,
WE GOT A BARN BURNER HERE. MY NAME is
Jon Stewart. Great show for you tonight.
Later on in this program, I'll be
talking to CNN's chief White House
correspondent, Kaitlan Collins. SHE'LL
BE JOINING US.
>> [cheering]
[applause]
[cheering]
>> AND WE'RE
>> [applause]
>> WE'RE GOING TO GET TO THE BOTTOM OF A
CRUCIAL ISSUE WITH JOURNALISM. How come
she doesn't smile when a weird old man
tells her to? [laughter]
We're going to start with the big news
from the weekend. The United States and
Iran
taking a hydration break.
>> [laughter]
>> A welcome cessation of hostilities. The
respite gave President Trump a chance to
stop bombing the Strait of Hormuz
and to start bombing
at the White House Correspondents
Dinner.
>> [laughter]
>> The other day, a senator I knew got a
text, a great guy,
from his wife.
And she said, "When you get home, I want
to have you immediately come up the
stairs and
make love to me."
And he said, "I can't do both."
You know what the hell you know.
In other words,
can't go up the stairs and make love.
Does anybody get that?
>> [laughter]
>> You know, normally I'd say don't quit
your day job, but in this case,
>> [cheering]
[applause]
>> I will make an
I I will MAKE AN EXCEPTION.
>> [laughter]
>> YES, FRIDAY NIGHT WAS the White House
CORRESPONDENTS DINNER, PARTY TIME.
Where the media elite got to hobnob with
hobgoblins.
If you remember, the first attempt ended
prematurely by, let's say,
very intense heckling.
The frightening scene prevented the
president from delivering his humorous
remarks, prepared remarks.
Which was a shame, because if there's
one thing that President Trump is known
for, it's his joyful love
of mirth.
>> We all know that he has a great sense of
humor. He's going to He's going to
deliver a really good speech.
>> I mean, he's he's funny.
>> He he is a hilarious entertainer.
>> His comedic timing is really good.
>> If he hadn't become president, he could
have become a stand-up comedian.
>> This guy is honestly one of the funniest
presidents we've ever had.
>> I think Trump's the funniest president
of all time.
>> Funny how? How the
is he funny?
Does he amuse you? HOW THE
WHAT'S SO FUNNY?
>> [laughter]
>> NO, SERIOUSLY, I AM asking you.
>> Because when I was watching him do that
that one joke, he doesn't seem very
funny at at all. Hey, but you know what,
man?
Look, I've been in that situation. We
all try new material. Doesn't go, you
move on to the next one. You cannot
judge Trump's whole hour-long special
just based on that one joke. Mr.
President, what else you got?
>> UFC Freedom 250 fight, and I'm pleased
to announce that we're going to host an
even bigger one
right in front of the White House every
Friday night.
>> See, this is great.
Simple premise, easy, refillable. We're
going to be hosting more fights. So,
these are just going to be jokes about
who's on the card, what the fights are
going to be. It's simple. Set up,
punchline.
Or,
>> [laughter]
>> It's every Friday night, every Saturday
night, we're going to have fights in
front of the White House.
Uh but we do have something coming
that's And I'm only kidding. You know,
the one thing about We are going to have
Indy 500. Roger Penske's coming in
mid-August. Germany, Japan, all these
countries, they spend billions and
billions of dollars trying to win the
Indy 500. On July 4th, we were over the
mall
and it was raining. Supposed to be
really bad again. And we didn't do it
the following day, and we didn't do it 2
weeks later. We did it when we were
supposed to do it. It was a fantastic uh
celebration.
>> [cheering]
[applause]
>> You set up the premise and then you just
walk off into the street?
MY BOSS IS SO CHEAP.
>> HOW CHEAP IS HE?
>> WELL, before I get to that
it was raining and
>> [laughter]
>> The guy went 4 minutes before
introducing the first joke fight in his
own premise.
>> But I can exclusively reveal to you this
evening that for the heaviest of the
heavyweights, we will have
sloppy Chris Christie, one of the
sloppiest human beings you'll ever meet,
fighting
uh I would say I could mention the
governor of Chicago, but I'm going to
mention instead Jerry Nadler.
>> WHAT? OH MY GOD!
YOU DON'T TELL US YOU'RE CHANGING THE
TARGET OF YOUR ROAST JOKE HALFWAY
THROUGH THE JOKE!
WE DON'T KNOW THE TARGET. Just change
it. Don't say I was going to make fun of
the governor of Illinois, BUT UH JERRY
NADLER. AND BY THE WAY, are there two
more relevant targets
than Chris Christie and Jerry Nadler?
Ooh, wait on the former governor of New
Jersey and outgoing Congressional
District 12 representative of New York.
Get a load of this.
Their careers will continue to have been
over.
But you know, look, I I don't I'm
>> [laughter]
>> You know what? It do- it The walk
doesn't matter as much as the the
destination. Let ple- Land this joke.
>> And they're fighting for a big piece of
cheesecake. Big fat piece of cheesecake.
Who the hell wrote that line?
>> [cheering]
[laughter]
>> Who wrote the line? Who the hell wrote
that line?
>> [laughter]
>> Um
it sounds like you.
It sounds exactly like something you
would say.
Look, this is a solid premise.
Let's try this again.
Here's an easy joke to land with this
premise. Oh, and tonight, uh I'm proud
to announce the next upcoming fight at
the White House. AOC will face off
against her greatest enemy, a simple
question about foreign policy. See, it's
simple.
Give Give that joke Give that joke a go.
>> And then you have a congresswoman
Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez and her three
>> doing her AOC plus three. That's her
three friends, right?
>> Okay.
>> AOC plus three and I watched her give
that answer when she was over in Europe.
It was not a good answer. If I ever gave
that answer, I would be out of politics.
>> You don't have to talk about what you
You
>> You cannot have a 19-second wait time.
Answer the simple
>> You do jokes.
>> But well, then have a rematch against an
extreme simple question on a foreign
policy.
>> NOBODY KNOWS WHAT YOU'RE SAYING NOW!
>> SECURITY CONFERENCE. IT WAS a big
security conference and this was her
first TIME UP IN
TERMS
>> NO!
>> terms of that and uh
>> You don't do jokes like you're reading
them for THE FIRST TIME!
>> [laughter]
>> GOD!
>> HE'S PUTTING 10 LB OF roast jokes in a 5
lb bag. It doesn't WORK THIS WAY. THERE
are rules to these things. Look, let's
just
Obviously, the more complex jokes you're
not going to be able to handle. Let's
just stick to simple burns. Simple
burns, you can't that up. Look, here we
go.
Here's what I'll do for you. I'll bring
out a red Here Here's what we're going
to do.
Here's I'm going to help you along.
Ready?
That's what we're going to do.
Here's what we're going [cheering] to
do.
We got the rim shot.
We're going to do simple burns. You
can't these up with your little
wandering off weaves. Go.
>> So, they thought about going with a
professional clown for entertainment,
but Adam Shifty Schiff was not
available.
You know, he's known I called him I I
hate some people, you know, I shouldn't
say this I'm president I'm not supposed
to hate I'm supposed to love everybody,
but he is a terrible person. He's a
liar.
>> [laughter]
[applause and cheering]
[applause]
>> Traditionally, roasts work because at
the heart
of it all, you only roast the ones you
love.
Saying you hate someone
in the middle of the joke really takes a
lot of the pleasure.
Don Rickles
might not have been the sensation he was
uh might not have been so beloved if he
ended his act with, "No, seriously,
THE JAPANESE.
>> [laughter]
>> I DON'T LIKE THEM AS PEOPLE.
>> Try again."
>> And uh I called him watermelon head cuz
he has the largest head I've ever seen
with the smallest neck, pencil neck. How
does that big fat ugly head stand on a
on a little pencil pencil pencil neck?
>> Okay, there's there's probably something
in there. But you might not be the
perfect messenger to deliver a roast
about someone's big fat ugly head.
>> [cheering]
>> It's another rule of roasting.
>> [applause]
>> It's just a difference.
VERY TOUGH TO LAND SOLID jokes about
something you yourself
clearly suffer from.
Although admittedly, your big fat ugly
head sits on what appears to be uh not a
pencil, but a big fat ugly neck.
So maybe the joke is a proportion issue.
Hard to point out the pencil neck when
your mug sits on what looks like a
rhinoceros's vagina.
>> [cheering]
[applause]
>> It's a rental.
Honestly, the only funny part of the
jokes was watching the crowd's
reactions. It was a mélange of
confusion, boredom, shock, and at one
point a literal EXISTENTIAL CRISIS.
AN EXISTENTIAL Here's the one thing you
never want from your audience at a
comedy show. YOU NEVER WANT THE AUDIENCE
AT YOUR COMEDY SHOW TO clearly be
rethinking the choices that led them to
that night.
Why? Why did I go to grad school?
The audience was so distraught and
perplexed that at times it was difficult
to discern whether you were watching
their reactions to Trump bombing at this
dinner
or their reactions to a gunman
interrupting the last one.
Which brings us to the hottest game show
of the summer season.
Shooting
or bombing?
NUMBER ONE.
MHM, milling about, some smiling, some
are filming, general sense of
uh that's a good mix of smooth humor, a
hint of concern or confusion.
The correct answer?
SHOOTING AFTERMATH. THAT WAS AFTER the
shooting aftermath.
Let's go to number two. Mhm.
Sadness and shock.
What happened?
How could this have happened?
>> [laughter]
>> The correct answer?
BOMBING.
THIS
>> [applause]
>> THIS DUDE, that's the face he made while
Trump was telling jokes.
Look at his face. He's literally like,
"Is anyone going to stop this madman?
People are going to get hurt."
Here's the next one.
Let's see. Okay, what is that? Is that
the shooting or the bombing?
All right, all right.
Obviously, that was after the shooting.
I knew you would get it pretty pretty
easy. I
I just wanted to remind everybody that
the night of the shooting RFK Jr. left
his wife to fend for herself.
>> [cheering]
>> No.
>> [applause]
>> There was no trick to it. I just thought
that was like the most up thing
I'd ever seen in my life.
>> [laughter]
>> Only room for one in the limo.
HERE'S ANOTHER QUICK ROAST RULE.
Try not to build a whole routine around
a premise that's no longer operable. You
can't have somebody like a J.B.
Pritzker, who I understand is not
president sadly, but uh
you know, some people say
never use the fat word, and I don't. I
would never call anybody fat. I have my
own problems, you know? It's not like
I'm perfect.
Sir, in the back. Don't call him a fat
pig, okay? You can't call
J.B. Pritzker a fat pig, please.
Actually, he's lost a lot of weight. I
saw him recently, he lost quite a bit of
weight.
>> [laughter]
>> Then why did YOU BRING IT UP?
YOUR MOTHER IS SO FAT.
ALTHOUGH NOW, OBVIOUSLY, she's on the
GLP-1s and uh
I mean, she does, if we're being honest,
look fant- I mean, here's what I'm Years
ago, when she sat around the house, SHE
REALLY SAT, ALTHOUGH I CAN'T SAY THAT
NOW. SHE'S A DRIVING FI-
The point IS THIS, YOUR MOTHER WAS WAS
SO FAT. I'm glad she got the help she
needed. Here, listen.
THE HEALTH BENEFIT GOD WILLING, she
lives to see those beautiful
grandchildren walking.
I promised myself I wouldn't cry.
The deeper problem for Trump
is that last weekend revealed he has
lived so long in a magical world of his
own creation, curated for his comfort
and positive reinforcement. He's the
ultimate snowflake, rewarded with
unearned participation trophy laughs.
But he doesn't even know what's actually
funny.
Because everything he says is funny in
his Truman Show of an administration.
>> I don't know if I can handle looking 20
lbs heavier.
>> [laughter]
>> Boy, you said the right thing. Thank
you.
That would have been the end of Crooked
Good steel. Right? As opposed to
green paper mache.
>> [laughter]
>> They do treat me well, Sharpie.
>> But of course the night demonstrated
another hard truth about Donald Trump's
administration.
That whenever his warm front of fantasy
collides with the cold front of reality,
there's no one to blame
but everyone else.
>> And they're fighting for a big piece of
cheesecake. Big fat piece of cheesecake.
Who the hell wrote that line? She wasn't
high up on her totem pole. Who the hell
wrote that? That was actually the only
thing I thought was good in this whole
freaking stupid speech that they wrote.
That was the only good one and that went
down with not exactly great laughter.
>> Well, you know what they say.
A great carpenter always blames his
tools.
And Donald Trump
is surrounded by tools.
But no matter how his writers
>> [applause]
[cheering]
[applause]
>> But no matter how uh his writers let him
down, boy Trump just kept digging.
Tried to make a simple joke about
Kaitlan Collins, but unfortunately
triggered himself in the process,
turning the entire event into a Festivus
grievance miracle.
>> But I want to personally congratulate
CNN's
Kaitlan Collins
on receiving her award.
It was all about me. It's It's fake. She
shouldn't get the award. It was a fake.
But I didn't mind. I said, "Caitlan,
congratulations."
But it was fake. There's no question
about it. But she's a
young, attractive woman. She never
smiles. I said, "Caitlan, do you ever
smile?
Smile.
You have a nice position. You're at CNN
fake news.
You should be a happy person. So, smile,
Caitlan. Just smile."
>> My favorite thing about is Wolf Blitzer
kept looking over like, "You want me to
him up? I'll go him up."
"You want me to get busy with him? I'll
go get
busy with
I'll go right up there and slam his head
down."
>> [applause]
>> "I'LL WILL SMITH THAT YOU
WANT ME TO WHIP THAT?"
"KEEP CAITLAN COLLINS' NAME
LOOK,
THIS WAS A BAD NIGHT. DON'T take my word
for it. Even Trump's cadre of media
fanboys and girls had to admit it.
>> I've seen him be very funny. Uh and so,
I think he could have been a lot
funnier.
>> I think it's a missed opportunity. It
really had no positive no positive
effect on anybody, including him.
>> it could have been a lot shorter and it
could have been punchier.
>> Some of the jokes veered off into very
uh sort of honorary insults.
Uh and that's not going to land for many
audiences.
>> That guy couldn't polish this turd?
That guy who spends his days bending
over backwards to figure out how to tell
you that the war in Iran is goo goo?
Even he's like, "I can't put lipstick on
this motherfucker."
Look, beyond the fact that Trump was
terrible, the dinner should not have
happened at all. In fact, it shouldn't
ever happen. Quite frankly,
memorializing the collegial and cozy
relationship between the press and those
that they cover is at best a very bad
look in normal times. I don't need to
see the cops and robbers getting along
at a banquet honoring our penal code.
You can celebrate the First Amendment
without asking your opponent in that
fight what he thinks. You already know
what he thinks.
>> We are a nation that no longer has a
free and fair press.
Fake news is all you get.
>> Fake news, fake reporting is what's
tearing this country apart.
>> These corrupt press, they corrupt.
>> Crooked, dishonest media. Just horrible
people. These are horrible people.
>> and evil people. Real dishonest people.
>> They're so bad for the country.
>> It's almost treasonous. I have to be
honest. It's almost treasonous.
>> And they are truly the enemy of the
people.
>> WHO WANTS DESSERT?
>> [laughter]
>> I'LL FIGHT YOU FOR THE LAST PIECE OF
CHEESECAKE.
LOOK, as much as I enjoyed Donald Trump
having to squirm through Wolf Blitzer
describing in vivid detail why the Wall
Street Journal won a reporting award, it
was the end of that tour de force that
demonstrated the perverse bargain the
entire night encapsulated.
>> The Journal's courageous reporting on
President Trump's past relationship with
financier Jeffrey Epstein triggered the
release of the so-called Epstein files,
thousands of documents that might
otherwise have remained hidden from the
public. And despite the president's
threat of a lawsuit, the Journal
published a story about a provocative
letter to Epstein bearing President
Trump's signature.
>> I loved being able to sit through that.
Wolf should have just kept going.
>> I mean, you should have seen the
they didn't release. I mean
This guy knows what I'm talking about.
>> But it was the next moment that for me
solidified that this event is worse than
pro forma.
It's actually an act of submission.
>> Trump quickly filed a $20 billion
lawsuit against the Journal revealing
reporter Khadija Safdar's home address.
>> [applause]
>> Her family had to be relocated.
>> I'm a little stinker.
She wrote an objectively true story
about my depraved relationship with
Jeffrey Epstein and I I got her life
threatened. Did I do that? [screaming]
I mean, you'd think you'd all be mad at
him.
But they're all in there just schmoozing
it up.
So he just gets to shake hands with the
leaders of a profession, with the
leaders of a profession whose members he
has subpoenaed, arrested, sued, cut
their funding, threatened their
licenses, barred their access, and even
had deported. And the sad truth
is if Trump had known he could win an
award for that Epstein story,
well,
he'd have told them about the Epstein
files himself.